Hey guys, we'll come back.
Now. You have seen the job running end
to end from data ingestion
to loading into the different layers in the data lake.
Now remember, this job is to be run monthly, right?
We get data EV every month, in fact from the
N-Y-C-T-L-C portal, which is our source for data.
And what we did in the previous step is we went to the step
function service and uh, ran the state machine
manually, right?
So this is good for development.
Yes, we're test developing a testing.
That's all fine, but when it comes to production, this has
to run automatically every month, okay?
For that, how do we do it?
We've gotta schedule it to run every month, okay?
So we have jobs in data engineer that are scheduled
and we have other types of jobs as well called
as even driven jobs.
We'll talk about them later. But
for this section is all about schedule jobs.
And we know for our use case we gotta be scheduling this.
So to schedule, go to Event Bridge,
there's a service which we'll use Event Bridge.
Click on that on the left, you have schedules here.
Click on the schedules, scroll down,
create a schedule for now.
We'll do a one time test and then we'll schedule it later.
For every month we'll just name, uh, it as one time test.
And then, uh, we just choose the date and time.
In 24 hour format, we'll choose 14 0 0. Alright?
And then, uh, we'll do, we'll study as off for now
and then we'll do next.
Now we have many templates here.
Our job is in step function.
We've gotta choose the step function, let's choose that
and then, uh, choose a state machine,
which is Mission DH Pipeline.
Let's scroll down and then click next.
Enable the schedule, keep it as it is, scroll down
and choose an existing role.
You already had this role that is given to you
by a team member and you already have it in your account.
So just search for mission, DEH, even bridge roll,
and then do a next, finally review it.
You're gonna be running it at your schedule time.
Target is our pipeline role is the right one.
In fact, even bridge roll will then create schedule.
So it is already enabled right now
and it shows here that it is set for so
and so date and time.
Okay? And the target is our state machine.
So let's quickly go to our state machine and take a look.
Okay? I'm gonna go, uh,
to back to the state machine right here.
I'll click on this and we'll just refresh it.
We'll wait, wait for the time and we'll refresh it.
There you go. It's already running now.
So essentially your event bridge
triggered this step function state machine automatically.
You don't do it manually. Okay?
We are gonna go back to even bridge
and we will delete that in the next video.
Let's see how we can schedule this on a monthly cadence.
Okay? Do this and then, uh, go to the next video.